<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "../../../../../../../lib/pkp/dtd/helpTopic.dtd">

<!--
  * 000000.xml
  *
  * Author: Božana Bokan, Center for Digital Systems (CeDiS), Freie Universität Berlin
  * Author: Marco Tullney, Technische Informationsbibliothek und Universitätsbibliothek Hannover (TIB/UB)
  * Last update: February 06, 2014  
  * Distributed under the GNU GPL v2. For full terms see the file docs/COPYING.
  *
  * VG Wort plugin help page. 
  *
  -->

<topic id="VGWortPlugin/topic/000000" locale="en_US" title="VG Wort Plugin" toc="index/toc/000000" key="VGWortPlugin.index">
	<section>
		<![CDATA[<p>The VG Wort plugin enables integration and management of the VG Wort pixel tags in OJS. Here you can order new pixel tags, assign the pixel tags to the articles, register them and view the VG Wort statistics. For more information, please read the VG Wort publisher documentation and see the <a href="#section1">notes</a> section below.</p><p><em>ALL.</em> All existing pixel tags in OJS with their private and public code, order date and current status are displayed here.</p><p><em>AVAILABLE.</em> New pixel tags can be ordered here. The available (not assigned) pixel tags in OJS with their private and public code, the domain they have to be registered at and their order date are displayed here. The pixel tag that is ordered in OJS but assigned to a text manually or outside the OJS should be deleted, because it can’t be used any more (a pixel tag can be assigned only once).</p><p>An available pixel tag can be assigned to an article in the submission summary view. Please, consider the <a href="#assignment">assignment notes</a> below and be aware that once assigned <strong>a pixel tag can not be unassigned from the text any more!</strong></p><p><em>UNREGISTERED.</em> The pixel tags assigned to articles in OJS with the article authors, the article tile and the assignment date are displayed here.</p><p>Directly before a text is registered a check is done if the assigned article is published, if there is a HTML or a PDF galley and if the VG Wort card numbers are valid. The registration is not possible if the pixel tag is removed.</p><p>For the registration, please consider the <a href="#registration">registration notes</a> below as well as the following recommendations:<ul><li>The text should be stable, i.e. not changing that much any more. Therefore, register a published text with a time delay (e.g. two weeks).</li><li>Register texts in the night (e.g. from 22:00 to 04:00), because of the lower VG Wort server load at that time.</li></ul></p><p>Please, be aware that <strong>a registration can not be changed or withdrawn!</strong></p><p>After a text is registered, it will be verified by the VG Wort stuff. If there are some problems, the VG Wort publisher account owner (whose username and password are set in the plugin settings by the journal manager) will be notified.</p><p><em>REGISTERED.</em> The registered pixel tags in OJS with their private code, the article authors, the article tile, the registration date and the current tracking status are displayed.</p><p>If the registration has to be changed or withdrawn, please contact VG Wort.</p><p>There is a possibility to manually insert already registered pixel tags (e.g. when moving from another system).</p><p><em>STATISTICS.</em> The overall VG Wort pixel tags statistics are shown here: the total amount of the ordered and tracked pixel tags till now as well as the statistics for the last 12 months about the ordered pixel tags, those the tracking is started for, the minimal access count is reached for and those not registered yet but with the minimal access count reached.</p>]]>
	</section>

	<section title="NOTES">
		<![CDATA[<p><em>Settings</em></p><p>PHP version 5.x >= 5.0.1, PHP Soap, and, PHP OpenSSL extension modules are required for the VG Wort services used here and thus for the plugin to work.</p><p>The VG Wort publisher account (username and password) set up by the journal manager in the plugin settings is used for the authentication and authorization for all VG Wort services used here (order, check, registration, statistics).</p><p>The editors selected by the journal manager in the plugin settings are allowed to use the VG Wort services and to manage the pixel tags.</p><p>The minimal amount of the available pixel tags is defined by the journal manager in the plugin settings. If the minimum of the available pixel tags is reached, the selected editors will be notified by an email and reminded to order new pixel tags.</p><p><em>Management</em></p><p>The pixel tags number, status and dates displayed on these pages are only for OJS internal use. They only concern the activities undertaken in OJS and can differ to the information in the VG Wort portal. The statistics on the other hand are the overall VG Wort statistics and concern not just OJS but the overall pixel tags activities. For example, the pixel tags that are ordered in the VG Wort portal or the pixel tags that are assigned and registered manually or outside from OJS will not be displayed here but they will be considered in the overall VG Wort statistics.</p><p><em>Order</em></p><p>The count of the new pixel tags should be more than the minimal amount of the available pixel tags defined in the plugin settings and less than 100.</p><p><a name="assignment"></a><em>Assignment</em></p><p>A valid VG Wort card number is required for each author that should take part in the payout of royalties. This means that the authors have to register at the VG Wort portal first. Upon the successful registration, a card number is assign to the VG Wort user. The card number should be entered in the article author metadata at the submission step 3 or editing the article metadata in the submission summary view. Also, the author's first and the last name have to be identical to those in the VG Wort portal.</p><p>VG Wort distinguishes between two text types: text (has to contain more than 1800 characters) and poem. The text type is to be defined at the assignment of a pixel tag to an article in the submission summary view.</p><p>Once assigned, a pixel tag can not be unassigned from the text any more! The VG Wort tracking starts as soon as the article is published and a pixel tag assigned. To stop the VG Wort tracking remove the pixel tag in the submission summary view. To enable the VG Wort tracking again reinsert the pixel tag. This will remove or reinsert the pixel tag in the galleys.</p><p>If the article access is restricted, please ensure that VG Wort has the acces, i.e. create an appropriate account for VG Wort and inform them.</p><p><a name="registration"></a><em>Registration</em></p><p>If there are translators that should take part in the payout of royalties, please register the text manually at the VG Wort portal, because it’s not possible to provide the required information about the translators in OJS.</p><p>The article, a pixel tag is assigned to, has to be published.</p><p>VG Wort considers only texts in HTML and PDF format. Thus, a galley in one of those two formats has to exist. Please, ensure that all galleys are uploaded in OJS before the registration.</p><p>The size of a galley must be less than 15MB.</p><p>For each HTML and PDF galley one web range with one URL will be registered. The case when an article extends over several web pages (a web range with several URLs) is not supported here.</p><p>Once a registration is done it can not be changed or withdrawn any more! The only possible change is the addition of new web ranges. For example, if a new galley (e.g. a text translation in another language) is uploaded after the registration or your domain name or URLs change, please log in at the VG Wort portal and add the appropriate web ranges manually. If a problem occurs and a registration has to be changed or withdrawn, please contact the VG Wort.</p><p>The correct registration is required for the payment of royalties.</p><p><em>Statistics</em></p><p>It takes min. 72 hours for a pixel tag to start be tracked in the VG Wort portal.</p>]]>
	</section>

</topic>
